Tokino Sora is a Japanese virtual idol who loves to sing and dance.
時乃空是一位熱愛唱歌和跳舞的日本虛擬偶像
As a virtual YouTube star, she is an energetic young girl
身為一位虛擬 YouTube 明星，她是充滿活力的年輕女孩
with a motherly attitude whose hobbies include singing and dancing,
同時又具有媽媽的屬性，她的興趣包括唱歌和跳舞
and a peculiar love for horror games.
並且很莫名地擅長遊玩恐怖遊戲
Working under the entertainment agency known as "Cover Corp,"
隸屬於「Cover Corp」的娛樂公司
Sora is the picturesque representative of Cover.
時乃空也是 Cover 的門面形象
She and her peers are one of the most internationally recognized groups of "Vtubers," called "Hololive."
她和她的同伴是最受國際認可的「Vtubers」團體之一，叫做「Hololive」
Being its very first talent and thus its progenitor, she was the one who carried Hololive on her
作為 Hololive 的首位人才，她正是那位支撐起整個 Hololive 的先驅
shoulders from day one.
從第一天就肩負著整個 Hololive 的重任
As such, she is a highly respected individual.
因此，她是一個非常受人尊敬的人
This reputation of hers was earned through her contributions
她的這種聲望是通過她的貢獻所獲得的
as one of the pioneers of this vibrant industry.
作為這個充滿活力的行業的先驅之一
Her emotional journey is filled with pride and determination, and shows us that anything
她的情感旅程充滿了驕傲與決心，並向我們展示
can be achieved, even at your own pace.
任何事物都能夠實現，甚至你可以按照自己的步伐
Her grand reputation and achievements could not come to be were it not for an exhausting
她的名譽與成就來自於
amount of hard work.
付出極大的辛勞
So who is Tokino Sora?
那麼，誰是時乃空？
(piano riff from Heroic Heroine)
(音樂：Heroic Heroine 片段)
Virtual YouTubers are an entertainment phenomena that was born in Japan,
「虛擬 YouTubers」 是在日本誕生的娛樂現象
which began sprouting in 2016.
始於2016年
This new phenomena features content creators who use virtual avatars to represent themselves.
特色是內容創作者使用虛擬角色來代表自己
The main medium used for their activities is in their name: YouTube.
他們活動的主要平台就如名字所示：YouTube
Permeating throughout Japanese entertainment media, this new industry started
在日本的娛樂媒體之間蔓延開來，新興產業崛起
with the debut of Kizuna Ai.
從Kizuna AI（絆愛）的初次亮相就開始了
Kizuna Ai was the first self-proclaimed Virtual YouTuber who debuted on December 1st, 2016.
絆愛是自稱第一位虛擬YouTuber，她於2016年12月1日首次登場
With her viral growth in early 2017, she paved the way for the industry to come,
她在2017年初的快速成長，為未來的行業鋪平了道路
marking herself as the progenitor of modern Vtubing.
標記自己為現代 Vtubing 的始祖。
Nowadays, the Vtuber industry features thousands of different Vtubers,
如今的 Vtuber 產業擁有數千個不同的 Vtubers
each with varied styles of presentation, specialities, and personalities.
每個人的表現方式、專長和個性都各不相同
There are gamers, singers, artists, programmers, and more.
這裡有遊戲玩家、歌手、藝術家、程式設計師，以及其他各種各樣的人
Among this diverse sea of virtual talent, stands the star of our show:
在這眾多的虛擬才藝海洋中，我們的主角矗立在其中：
Tokino Sora
時乃空
A shy but cheerful girl with a grandiose dream.
一個害羞但快樂的女孩，有著宏大的夢想
Sora began her entertainment career on September 7th, 2017
時乃空於 2017 年 9 月 7 日出道
on NicoNicoDouga, a Japanese parallel to YouTube
在 NicoNico 動畫，可以說是「日本的 YouTube」
By today's standard, when a new Vtuber appears for the first time,
以今天的標準來看，當一個新的 Vtuber 首次直播時（初配信）
there is often a huge amount of viewership,
應該會有很大的同時觀看量（同接數）
regarding it as something to be celebrated.
將它視為值得慶祝的事情
In the case of Hololive,
在 Hololive 裡面
when new Vtubers debut, it’s common for them to reach upwards of
當新的 Vtuber 初次配信時，他們通常會有著...
hundreds of thousands of viewers and subscribers for their very first stream.
超過十萬以上的觀眾和訂閱者在他們的初配信中
By comparison, discounting any staff, Sora’s first stream had thirteen
相比之下時乃空的初配信，在去除工作人員的數量下，只有 13 個觀眾
On October 19th 2017, as celebration for reaching 100 subscribers,
在 2017 年 10 月 19 日，為了慶祝達到 100 位訂閱者
her model received a minor update.
她的虛擬外觀模型進行了小幅度的更新
Later, on Halloween, she received a new costume, accessories, and an unnamed mascot,
後來，在萬聖節那天，她收到了新的服裝、配件，還有一個未命名的吉祥物，
who would later be named Ankimo.
後來被命名為鮟鱇肝
Despite all these new changes, her subscription count hadn’t noticeably risen.
儘管做了這些新的變動，她的訂閱數並未明顯上升
A-chan and the staff considered giving up livestreams altogether
A 醬和工作人員考慮完全放棄直播
in favour of YouTube videos but Sora refused.
其他成員選擇改做 YouTube 影片，但 Sora 卻一口拒絕
Instead, she worked harder to improve her livestream performance, exploring other platforms
相反的，她更努力地提升她的直播表現，並探索其他平台
like Line,
像是Line
17live, TikTok, and focusing on conversing with her audience and fans.
17live、TikTok、並專注於與她的觀眾和粉絲進行對話
But what is an entertainer without her fans?
但是，如果沒有粉絲，一個表演者又算是什麼呢？
Sora’s slow but steady rise to popularity garnered her a loyal fanbase,
時乃空的穩健人氣上升為她贏得了一群忠實的粉絲
which did not have a name to call themselves.
這時粉絲還沒有特別的稱呼
So on November 2nd, 2017, Sora hosted a poll to see what name best suited her fans.
所以在 2017 年 11 月 2 日，時乃空舉辦了一項投票： 選出最適合她的粉絲的名字
There were many suggestions like Tokitomo, Sorabuds, Soragang and Soraves (slaves),
有許多建議，像是時之友、空哥兒們、空幫派和空奴隸...
but one name stood out among the rest and that’s how the name “Soratomo” was chosen
但有一個名子脫穎而出，那就是「空友」。
as the official fan name for her fans.
這是她粉絲的官方粉絲名稱
By December 23rd, 2017, Sora's subscriber count reached 1,000.
到 2017 年 12 月 23 日為止，時乃空的訂閱者數達到了1,000人！
It was a huge number for her, but meager at the time when compared to Kizuna Ai and the other
這對她來說以經是一個巨大的成就
Heavenly Kings.
相較於絆愛和其他天王級的 Vtubers
However on Christmas 2017, a miracle occurred.
然而在 2017 年聖誕節，一個奇蹟發生了
According to JP Soratomos, Dennou Shojo Siro suffered technical issues mid-stream,
根據日本的空友說明，另一位天王 Vtuber「電腦少女小白」在直播途中遇到了技術問題
and while waiting for the stream to be fixed, many decided to watch Sora instead
而在等待直播修復的同時，許多人轉而觀看時乃空的直播
and were smitten by her charm and personality.
然後人們就被她的魅力和個性所吸引了
This boosted her subscriber growth and granted her a significant increase in viewers.
這讓她的訂閱者數量迅速增長，觀眾急速增加
This abrupt rise shot her subscriber count up to over 3,000 by the end of Christmas,
這種突然的成長使她的訂閱數在聖誕節結束時超過了 3,000
and skyrocketed her straight up to 20,000 at the start of 2018.
並讓她在 2018 年初直接猛增至 20000
This sudden rise was quite the sight to behold - truly, a Christmas Miracle.
這突然的上升實在是太驚人了 — 真的是聖誕奇蹟
With Sora’s rise in popularity we have yet to know what drives her to be a Vtuber,
隨著時乃空的人氣上升，我們還不知道是什麼驅使她成為一名Vtuber
what makes her want to perform in front of thousands of people.
是什麼讓她想要在數千人面前表演？
So, what is her goal?
那麼，她的目標是什麼呢？
What is Tokino Sora’s dream?
時乃空的夢想是什麼？
On December 28th 2017, Sora explained that when she was a child,
2017 年 12 月 28 日，時乃空解釋說，當她還是個小孩的時候，
her mother brought her to a concert at Yokohama Arena.
她的母親帶她去橫濱體育館的一場音樂會
She told Sora that one day, she wanted to see her daughter up there.
她告訴小空，有一天希望能看到自己的女兒在那上面
And from that day forward, Sora made it her dream to have original songs,
從那天開始，時乃空把創作原創歌曲作為她的夢想
and to one day be able to perform on stage at Yokohama Arena.
並且有一天能夠在橫濱體育館的舞台上演出
But to be an idol takes a lot of hard work and dedication.
但要成為偶像需要付出很多的努力和專注力
Then, what challenges does she have in front of her, on the way to achieving her idol dream?
那麼，她在實現偶像夢想的路上面臨著什麼挑戰呢？
(ending portion of Kotoba Kaze)
（音樂：Kotoba Kaze 的片段）
After the Christmas Miracle, Sora's subscriber count continued to climb rapidly,
時乃空的訂閱數量在聖誕奇蹟後持續高速攀升
shooting up to 20,000 at the start of 2018.
在 2018 年初，數字一口氣衝到了 20,000！！！
To start off the new year, Sora had her first ever company collaboration
在新的一年開始時，時乃空進行了她第一次的公司連動
with MirrativQ on January 5th and the 17th.
與 MirrativQ 在 1 月 5 日和 17 日
She was the Emcee for the event.
她是該活動的主持人
It's MirrativQ time!
現在是 MirrativQ 的時刻唷!
The event was a quiz event, where viewers would participate via the Mirrativ app if they answered questions correctly.
這活動是一個測驗活動，觀眾若在 Mirrativ app 上回答問題正確，就能參加
This brand new opportunity was a spotlight for Sora,
這個全新的機會原本是時乃空的聚光燈
which quickly turned the first step of her dream into a nightmare.
但很快地她的夢想卻變成了一場惡夢...
The event was plagued with endless technical problems and many viewers were unable to participate in the event,
活動被無止境的技術問題所困擾...許多觀眾無法參加這個活動...
or were disconnected halfway through.
或者在進行中途斷線了
The number of participants started at 446 then rapidly dropped down to 47.
參與者的人數開始時是 446 人，然後迅速下降到 47 人...
Losing around 90% of the participants was so alarming to the point that the event was almost called off.
失去大約 90% 的參賽者令人驚訝到幾乎要取消活動
Fortunately, despite all the difficulties, one participant managed to answer all of the questions.
幸運的是，有一位參與者排除所有困難、堅持下來... 成功回答了所有的問題！
This Soratomo persevered and was dubbed “Leonidas”  by the fans.
這位空友堅持不懈，因此被粉絲封為「列奧尼達」（斯巴達戰士名稱）
The legendary deeds of Leonidas were forever immortalized
列奧尼達的傳奇事蹟被永遠地銘記在歷史中
when Sora symbolically included them in her cover MV of Solar System Disco.
後來小空象徵性地將列奧尼達放入她的「太陽系 Disco」翻唱 MV 中
After the event, during an after-talk stream, she cried on stream for the first time.
活動結束後的雜談直播中，她第一次在直播中落淚...
This is something that she had promised never to show in front of her fans -
這是她承諾永不在粉絲面前露出的一件事
that she would never cry out of sadness, but only out of joy.
她永遠不會因為悲傷而哭泣，只有在喜悅時才會
Inspired by Sora’s determination, some Soratomos decided to create a beautiful song for her,
受到時乃空的決心所啟發，一些空友決定為她創作一首美麗的歌曲
and Sora released it as her very first soraSong, Yumeiro Asterisk.
並且時乃空將它作為她的第一首時乃空的歌曲：夢色時空
An original song composed by a Soratomo with Sora’s image as their theme.
以小空形象為主題的空友創作原創歌曲
Sora’s popularity continuing to rise was a spectacle to behold that was nothing short of astonishing.
時乃空人氣持續上升的景象無疑是震撼人心的
Described by A-chan herself, Sora was “the woman who swam too late to catch the big wave.”
A 醬說過：空是「游得太晚，無法趕上大浪的女人」
Despite this, by March 2018, her subscriber count broke through another barrier,
儘管如此，到了 2018 年 3 月，她的訂閱者數量突破了另一個障礙
surpassing 100,000, in spite of criticism of being a “Kizuna Ai clone.”
即使在當時小空被批評為「絆愛」的仿製品，訂閱就是超過了十萬人！
With the support of her Soratomos, Sora endured,
在她的「空友」的支援下，空堅持了下來
promising to keep moving forward one step at a time and never stopping,
承諾一步一步前進，永不停息
like a star shining in the night sky. A true idol…
就像夜空中閃耀的星星一樣。一個真正的偶像...
On May 18th, 2018, Sora made her first transformation into an idol by debuting her idol outfit.
2018 年 5 月 18 日，時乃空首次轉型為偶像，展示了她的偶像服裝
Achieving the first big step on the path to Yokohama Arena was a monumental and emotional event.
首次踏上通往橫濱競技場的道路，這是一個巨大而感人的事件
One could not help but cheer, watching Sora continue to grow.
看著空的成長，人們不自覺地為她打氣
But the road to becoming an idol is more than just changing a costume.
但是成為偶像的道路，絕不只是換衣服那麼簡單
She would have to continue to prove her determination through her actions in the years to come.
她將不得不在未來的幾年中通過行動繼續證明她的決心
Throughout 2018, she participated in various concerts including Rage Virtual Youtuber Grand Prix,
在 2018 年中，她參加了各種音樂會，包括 RAGE Virtual YouTuber GRAND PRIX
Nico Nico Cho Party (pictured), and Tubeout! Vol.1.
Nico Nico Cho Party (如圖)，還有 Tubeout! Vol.1。
2018 was a great year of growth for Sora, with her idol activities only continuing to ramp up in 2019.
2018年是時乃空成長的豐收年，她的偶像活動在2019年只會更加活躍。
To kick things off, she made a special announcement that would mark a monumental point in her idol career.
首先，她發表了一項特殊的宣布，這將是她偶像生涯中的一個重大時刻。
Presenting herself as a Virtual Idol,
她將自己呈現為一名虛擬偶像。
in March 2019 she announced a recording contract with one of the largest recording labels in Japan
2019年三月，她宣布與日本最大的幾家錄音廠之一簽訂錄音合約。
Victor Entertainment.
Victor娛樂公司。
Furthermore, she also announced her first album Dreaming.
此外，她也宣布了她的首張專輯《夢想》。
This event uniquely placed herself as one of the few Vtubers with a recording label.
這個活動使她成為少數擁有錄音品牌的Vtuber之一。
In April of that year, she starred in a TV drama named
在那年的四月，她主演了一部名為的電視劇
Watanuki-san Chi no.
渡請先生之家。
It’s a 2-season drama focusing on the lives of three sisters
這是一部分為兩季的戲劇，著重描述三個姊妹的生活
living together in Tokyo after losing their parents.
在失去父母後，他們在東京同住。
Sora played the major role of the eldest sister, Watanuki Ichika.
空擔任了大姐大的角色，渡烏一千賀。
This was the second TV show that Sora had a part in.
這是時乃空參與的第二部電視節目。
The first being Virtual-san wa Miteiru where she only got a minor role.
首部作品是「虛擬小姐在看」，她在裡面只擔任了一個小角色。
In addition to that, she also released her own light novel on April 29th
除此之外，她也在四月二十九日發布了她自己的輕小說
titled Tokino Sora: Virtual Idol Dakedo Ouen Shite Kuremasu ka?
標題為時乃空：雖然我是虛擬偶像但可以支持我嗎？
This LN tells the story of Sora in her early days,
這部輕小說講述了Sora早期的故事，
the challenges and the struggles that she and her team had been through.
她和她的團隊所經歷的挑戰與困苦。
With all the big achievements that she garnered, she finally received her second major model upgrade on June 27th, 2019.
在她取得所有的重大成就後，她終於在2019年6月27日接受了她的第二次重大模型升級。
This new model made her look slimmer, more stylish, and more idol-like.
這新的模型使她看起來更瘦，更時髦，更像偶像。
With this new model, Sora was ready to take on her first major step as a solo idol.
有了這個新模型，Sora已經準備好要邁出她作為獨唱偶像的第一大步。
So on October 6th, 2019, Sora got to perform her first ever solo concert:
所以在2019年10月6日，空首次進行了她的個人演唱會：
Dream! at Veats Shibuya.
於Veats Shibuya的Dream!
Performing Hololive On Stage - DayDream in the afternoon the same day,
在同一天的下午在Hololive舞台上演出 - DayDream，
Sora's first concert followed later that night which was an amazing performance.
時乃空同一晚的首場音樂會展示了精彩絕倫的演出。
As the title portrays, Dream! was truly a dream come true,
如同標題所描繪的，夢！真的就像是夢想成真，
and this would only be the first of many solo concerts that she would have.
這只是她舉辦的許多獨唱會中的第一場。
2019 was one of the busiest and greatest years for Sora.
Sora在2019年度有最忙碌且最豐富的一年。
She was so busy to the point that it pushed her to exhaustion.
她的忙碌程度到了她快要筋疲力盡的地步。
Yet despite that, she never stopped due to the support of her family, friends and fans.
然而，儘管如此，由於家人、朋友和粉絲的支持，她從未停止過。
On top of all the major events, she also collaborated with other Vtubers on the album Imagination Vol.1
除了所有的重大事件外，她還與其他 Vtuber 合作在專輯「Imagination Vol.1」上。
while her cover song Alien Alien achieved a whopping 10-million view to date.
而她翻唱的歌曲《Alien Alien》至今已突破一千萬觀看次數。
To top things off, she also reached 250k subscribers that year.
而且，她在那一年也達到了25萬訂閱者。
Although Sora has garnered many accomplishments that year,
儘管那年時乃空獲得了許多成就，
the road to Yokohama Arena remained long with many challenges to face.
前往橫濱體育館的道路仍很長，須面對許多挑戰。
As the new year of 2020 began, Sora and the other Hololive members performed their first group idol concert,
當2020年的新年開始時，Sora和其他Hololive成員進行了他們的第一場團體偶像演唱會，
aptly named Non-stop Story.
恰如其分地命名為《不停的故事》。
The concert took place on January 24th at Toyosu Pit.
音樂會在1月24日於豐洲PIT舉行。
The ending song that they used for the concert was one of Sora’s original songs - Dream Story
他們在演唱會上用的結尾曲是時乃空的原創歌曲 - 「夢之故事」
- but with a slight twist.
- 但有著輕微的改變。
Its lyrics were slightly adjusted from
它的歌詞稍微進行了一些調整，
“Tokino Sora da yo!” to “Hololive da yo!”.
的可能性從「我是時乃空！」到「我是Hololive！」。
This edit was suggested by Sora herself.
這個編輯是由時乃空本人建議的。
Later that year, she also released a mini-Album: My Loving on March 4th
那年稍後，她在三月四號也發行了一張迷你專輯：My Loving
and also her first photo book titled SoraBiyori.
以及她的首本照片書「SoraBiyori」。
Things were looking good for Sora but as 2020 progressed, the world shook in the wake of the Covid-19 pandemic.
對空來說，事情原本一切順利，但隨著2020年的進行，新冠病毒大流行使世界震驚。
This world-shaking event affected Sora, where some of her activities like streaming, had to be halted or delayed.
這個震撼全世界的事件影響到了時乃空，她的一些活動，如直播，不得不被暫停或延遲。
Even her birthday celebration stream was postponed.
連她的生日慶祝直播也被延後了。
In response to the pandemic, she streamed more frequently from home, and even did her very first guerilla stream.
回應疫情，她在家裡更頻繁地進行直播，甚至進行了她首次的突擊直播。
This was a new experience for her because previously,
這對她來說是一種新的體驗，因為之前，
she mainly streamed from the studio with all the staff at her side since it’s easier for them to manage her idol activities.
她主要在所有工作人員旁邊的工作室直播，因為這樣他們更容易管理她的偶像活動。
On her 20th Birthday, she released Aozora no Symphony, a song she personally wrote for her Soratomos.
在她20歲生日那天，她發布了《Aozora no Symphony》這首她親自為她的空友們寫的歌曲。
During an interview, when asked about her feelings about this song, she said,
在訪談中，當被問到對這首歌的感想時，她說，
It feels like I’m putting my whole self out there, it’s not easy to get used to.
感覺就像我把整個自己暴露出去，這並不容易適應。
I think it is a special song, containing both the happiness of having someone who is pleased by the song,
我認為這是一首特別的歌，融合了有人喜歡這首歌的快樂。
and the uneasiness of it.
以及它所帶來的不安。
The lyrics are totally plain, but I figured I should express how I felt to the greatest degree possible.
歌詞完全是簡單的，但我認為我應該盡可能地表達我的感情。
Being too honest might have its drawbacks, but I think if you’re living honestly, you can have a blessed life.
過於誠實可能會有缺點，但我認為如果你活得誠實，你就能過上幸福的生活。
So on a fundamental level, I’m happy with who I am.
所以在根本上，我對自己的身份感到開心。
In June 2020, she celebrated her belated birthday alongside her alter ego, Yoruno Sora.
在2020年6月，她與她的分身宵野空一起慶祝了遲來的生日。
Unlike Tokino Sora, Yoruno Sora is a much more quiet version of herself
與時乃空不同，夜之空是她自我更安靜的版本。
where she has a much deeper voice and a more relaxed aura.
她的聲音更深沉，氣場也更加鬆散。
The song that “they” performed together was Instant Heaven.
他們一起演唱的歌曲是 Instant Heaven。
Continuing on to September for her 3rd anniversary, she got another model upgrade.
繼續到9月為了她的三週年紀念，她又再次升級了模型。
This is undoubtedly her most popular and cutest model to date.
這無疑是她至今最受歡迎也最可愛的造型。
During the anniversary stream, her longtime friend and colleague,
在周年紀念直播中，她的多年好友和同事，
A-chan wrote an emotional letter for her.
A-chan 給她寫下了一封充滿情感的信。
It had been a tough journey for them, but they did not falter and persevered until their hard work came to fruition.
對他們來說，這一路上充滿艱難，但他們並未動搖，堅持到底，直到他們的努力終於得到了回報。
In that same month, she also held a concert with AZKi, titled Setsunatik Chronicles,
同月，她與AZKi一同舉辦了名為「Setsunatik Chronicles」的音樂會，
alongside the release of their single Kurenai Chronicles
隨著他們的單曲《紅色編年史》的發行。
Sora’s popularity as an idol kept on soaring even higher
時乃空作為偶像的人氣持續不斷升高
to the point where she even managed to cross through the barrier between "virtual" and "real".
甚至超越了“虛擬”和“真實”之間的屏障。
Tokyo Idol Festival is an annual event featuring performances from idols and idol groups from all over Japan.
東京偶像節是一年一度的活動，來自日本各地的偶像和偶像團體將在此進行表演。
That year, they had decided to host their first ever online festival to celebrate
那年，他們決定首次舉辦線上節慶進行慶祝
not only real world idols, but even virtual ones.
不僅是真實世界的偶像，甚至是虛擬的也一樣。
Sora was selected as their first Virtual Emcee from October 2nd to October 4th, 2020.
從2020年10月2日到10月4日，空被選為第一位虛擬主持人。
Needless to say, she did a spectacular job.
不用說，她的表現十分出色。
After having hosted TIF 2020, she announced her second album On Stage! on October 21st.
在主持了2020年的TIF之後，她在10月21日宣布了她的第二張專輯「On Stage！」。
This signified another big step towards her dream.
這象徵著她朝夢想又邁出了重要的一步。
The album is packed with her feelings and memories with her Soratomos,
這張專輯充滿了她與 Soratomos 的感情和回憶，
showcasing not just her desire to realize her dream,
展現的不僅僅是她實現夢想的渴望，
but to stand together with everyone who had supported her along the way.
但是要和一路上支持她的每一個人站在一起。
Soon after the album's release, she also performed her 2nd Solo concert Parallel Time.
專輯發行不久後，她也開展了她的第二場獨唱音樂會「平行時空」。
Parallel Time was performed exclusively online through SPWN.
Parallel Time是通過SPWN在線進行的專屬表演。
It was an emotional and energetic event which showcased the culmination of Sora’s past 3 years;
這是一場充滿情感與活力的事件，展現了時乃空過去三年的精彩結晶；
her experience, her talents, her skills, were all showcased here.
她的經驗，她的才華，她的技巧，都在這裡展現無遺。
The pandemic had halted many operations across many industries but for Sora, that didn’t stop her.
疫情停止了許多行業的運營，但對Sora來說，她並沒有停下來。
Since people were pressured into staying at home or in isolation, the consumption of digital entertainment had increased.
自從人們被迫待在家裡或者自我隔離之後，數位娛樂的消費量增加了。
This rising desire for entertainment lifted all Vtubers to boom in popularity.
這種娛樂的渴望使所有的Vtuber都人氣狂飆。
As a result, Hololive and the Vtuber industry grew dramatically,
結果，Hololive 和 Vtuber 產業劇增，
with Sora herself reaching 500,000 subscribers on October 26th, 2020,
時乃空在2020年10月26日達到了五十萬訂閱者。
doubling her subscribers from the previous year.
她的訂閱者數量相比前一年翻了一番。
Sora had the will and perseverance to achieve her dream.
空有著實現夢想的意志和毅力。
She always pushes herself to be an idol everyone can be proud of, being a beacon of hope and inspiration.
她總是鞭策自己，要成為每個人都可以為之驕傲的偶像，成為希望和啟示的燈塔。
By 2021, Sora had reached heights that she couldn’t even have imagined when she first started.
到了2021年，空已經達到了她在剛開始時甚至無法想像的高度。
On November 2021, she released her third album Re:Play , which primarily consists of cover songs.
2021年11月，她發布了她的第三張專輯Re:Play，主要由翻唱歌曲組成。
This album is filled with songs that she’s interested in or already used to singing during her karaoke streams.
這張專輯充滿了她有興趣的或在她的卡拉OK直播中常唱的歌曲。
When asked about her thoughts on the album, she mentioned that it was a nice change of pace
當被問及她對專輯的看法時，她提到這是一種很好的節奏變化。
for her since she was always interested in making an album full of cover songs at least once.
她一直都很喜歡做一張全是翻唱歌曲的專輯。
Throughout that year, there was a lot of merchandise being made in her image, like plushies and ceramic dolls.
那一整年，有許多以她形象製作的商品，如玩偶和陶瓷娃娃。
She was even made into cards for TCGs (Trading Card Games), such as Rebirth and Weiss Schwarz.
她甚至被製作成為TCGs（交換卡片遊戲）如Rebirth和Weiss Schwarz的卡片。
Furthermore, she was also selected as the representative of VTubers for the 18th Tokyo International Music Market.
此外，她也被選為第18屆東京國際音樂市場的VTubers代表。
And finally, she unveiled her first casual attire on March 3rd,
最後，她在3月3日首次公開了她的休閒服裝，
which she had been lacking for a long time since all her major outfits thus far were idol costumes.
她一直以來缺乏的，因為她到目前為止所有的主要服裝都是偶像服裝。
We are witnessing Sora’s growth as a Vtuber, but more importantly, as an IDOL, and her journey is far from over.
我們正在見證時乃空作為Vtuber的成長，但更重要的是，作為一個偶像，她的旅程還遠未結束。
There are so many Vtubers with a variety of gimmicks, backstories and designs.
有許多Vtuber有各種各樣的噱頭，背景故事和設計。
There are also some who aspire to be singers and idols themselves.
也有一些人渴望成為歌手和偶像。
So why are we supporting Sora?
那麼，我們為什麼要支持空呢？
What makes us put in all the effort to make a video about her, for this normal looking girl?
是什麼讓我們花費所有心力，為這個看起來普通的女孩製作影片呢？
(Ending of Chu-Chu-Lu!)
(Chu-Chu-Lu!的結束)
Sora has been part of the Vtuber industry since 2017 and an idol since 2018.
空從2017年起就在Vtuber行業裡活躍，並且從2018年起成為了偶像。
She has been called by many names:
她被稱為許多名字：
Tokino Sora
時乃空
Sora-mama
空媽媽
Sora-neesan
空姐姐
Sora-senpai is an idol
空前輩是一位偶像
Tokino Soda
時乃蘇打
But the core part of Sora’s identity is being a normal girl with a humble attitude,
但素雅態度與樸素的女孩形象才是時乃空的核心風采。
a heartwarming personality, and a magnificent dream.
一個讓人感到溫暖的性格，以及宏偉的夢想。
People naturally gravitate to Sora with her amazing singing talent,
人們自然而然會被空的驚人歌唱才能所吸引，
and for being an idol who talks to fans as if they are her family - even after becoming a celebrity.
甚至在成為名人後，依然視粉絲如家人般交談的偶像，
While making this video, we decided to ask Soratomos:
在製作這個影片的時候，我們決定向空友們發問：
Why do you root for Sora?
為什麼你會為時乃空加油呢？
We had 73 responses to our poll.
我們的民意調查共收到了73份回應。
The most frequent reason why Soratomos love Sora is because of her charming personality.
索拉朋友最常見的喜歡空的原因，就是她迷人的個性。
Soratomos see her as a relaxing, down to earth, polite and comforting dork, with a humble, positive and calm attitude.
空友們認為她是一個讓人放鬆、腳踏實地、有禮且安慰人心的笨蛋，具有謙遜、積極和冷靜的態度。
Other reasons included her ability to sing, as well as her cuteness.
其他原因包含她的歌唱才能，以及她的可愛。
Many responses in Japanese noted that Sora’s singing makes them feel better.
許多日本的回應都指出，時乃空的歌聲讓他們感到心情愉快。
By the time of this recording we are celebrating her reaching one million Youtube subscribers and her 5th anniversary.
在這次錄製時，我們正在慶祝她的 Youtube 訂閱者突破一百萬，並慶祝她的第五個週年。
We are rooting for her to realize her dream because it shows that even a normal girl can reach big heights.
我們為她實現夢想而加油，因為這證明了即使是一個普通的女孩也能達到很大的高度。
She motivates us to push harder - even just a little,
她激勵我們更加努力 - 即使只是一點點，
and even a tweet from her saying we should take care of our health is enough to motivate a lot of people.
甚至連她發的一條提醒我們要照顧好自己的身體的推特都足以激勵很多人。
For us, she is a genuine and hardworking idol and we couldn't be any prouder of her achievements.
對我們來說，她是一位真誠並努力的偶像，我們對她的成就感到無比的驕傲。
We can't wait to see how much more she will accomplish to reach Yokohama Arena and beyond.
我們迫不及待地想看到她將會如何達成更多目標，甚至超越橫濱體育館。
Sora is very soft spoken, but confident. She follows her own pace, and is considerate of others.
時乃空說話的語氣很溫柔，但卻很自信。她按自己的節奏行事，且很替他人著想。
She will never deliberately overshadow anyone and will always support them as everyone supports her.
她永遠不會故意搶走其他人的風采，她會像所有人支持她一樣去支持他們。
A firm pillar to many people.
對許多人來說是堅定的支柱。
She’s able to inspire them like a traditional idol and is always earnest to a fault.
她能像傳統偶像那樣激勵他們，並且總是誠懇到讓人心疼。
The progress of Sora’s subscription count is often outpaced by her peers in the Vtuber industry.
時乃空的訂閱增長速度，常常被她的其他虛擬網紅同行超越。
One can say that her design in comparison may seem plain like water, but that in itself can be a good thing.
人們可以說她的設計相比之下可能看起來如水一般平淡，但這本身就是一件好事。
She will not force you to watch her, but instead she wants you to take care of yourself first both mentally and financially.
她不會強迫你看她，反而她希望你先照顧好自己的心理和經濟狀況。
For her, any kind of support, such as watching her streams or drawing Sora art will make her happy.
對她來說，任何形式的支持，例如觀看她的直播或者畫她的藝術品，都會讓她感到開心。
Sora’s streams provide Soratomos a comfortable and warm vibe,
時乃空的串流給「時乃友」帶來了舒適溫馨的氛圍，
that even if we watch other Vtubers, she is watching with us.
即使我們在看其他的 Vtubers，她也會和我們一起看。
When we watch Sora’s streams, she makes us feel like we are “coming home.”
當我們觀看時乃空的直播時，她讓我們感到如同「回到家」的溫馨。
This is the end of our video of Tokino Sora’s journey, but she still has a long road ahead of her.
這是我們關於時乃空之旅的視頻結束了，但她的前路還很漫長。
Her journey, which began as a high school girl Vtuber,
她的旅程，始於身為高中生 Vtuber，
transformed her into the foundational pillar of Hololive,
將她轉變成Hololive的基礎之柱，
and into the idol that we cheer for today,
並成為我們今天所歡呼的偶像，
supporting her to help her achieve her dreams..
為了幫助她實現夢想而支持她..
When you are stressed or unmotivated, you can always count on Sora to brighten up your day
當你感到壓力大或缺乏動力時，你可以總是依賴時乃空讓你的一天充滿活力。
like the idol that she is.
如同她是偶像一般。
She will give you the motivation to move.
她將給你前進的動力。
Just remember,
只要記住，
to Step and Go.
走一步又一步。
(Step and Go)
(步伐與前進)